# **QUANG DUONG**

### **CONTACT INFORMATION -**

Office 5.408B
Gates Dell Complex
Department of Computer Science
The University of Texas at Austin
Austin, Texas 78712

E-Mail: duongquang1@gmail.com

Phone: (832) 335 - 4818 Website: selfdeprecated.dev GitHub: github.com/Quangmire

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/duongguang1

#### **RESEARCH INTERESTS -**

My research focuses on adapting machine learning approaches to improve performance over classical computer architecture predictors. Namely, I am interested in different techniques such as saliency, distillation, and compression to produce practical predictors from ML models for on-chip real-time inference.

### **EDUCATION** ---

- · Ph.D. in Computer Science
- · Advisor: Calvin Lin
- · Current GPA: 4.0000

## 

- · B.S./M.S. in Computer Science
- · B.S. in Mathematics (Specialization in Scientific Computing)
- · Summa Cum Laude
- · Cumulative GPA: 3.9482

#### EXPERIENCE ----

- Utilized saliency information to adapt statically trained neural branch prediction models to allow for on-chip training
- Examining saliency and distillation techniques to prune existing neural data prefetchers to improve their practicality

- · Analyzed performance issues across different analyst workloads
- Proposed and implemented data format restructuring that yielded a 4-10x speedup in processing time
- Migrated code base from Python 2 to 3 and wrapped legacy C++ code into Python libraries with SWIG and Cython to streamline data analysis

- Leveraged clustering and reinforcement learning techniques to iteratively refine estimations of ionospheric model parameters competitive with commercial software
- Optimized run-time by adaptively executing physical simulations at different granularities based on approximations of the objective surface for real-time execution

<ul> <li>Honors Scholar</li></ul>	
denoised ionosonde information via multi-layer perceptrons  Texas Institute for Discovery Education in Science Fellowship	
College of Natural Sciences at The University of Texas at Austin	
<ul> <li>Analyzed different Pareto frontiers by weighting the objective function for the 3D model approximation genetic algorithm that traded off generated OpenSCAD code complexity with convergence and error rate to allow for downstream non-expert modification</li> <li>Implemented vectorized voxelization code to approximate expensive objective functions</li> </ul>	
<b>Freshman Research Initiative Fellowship</b>	
<ul> <li>Adapted CPPN-NEAT algorithm to grow increasingly complex neural networks as functional approximations of 3D models</li> </ul>	
<ul> <li>Generated OpenSCAD's model descriptor language using the neural network output</li> </ul>	
TEACHING ————————————————————————————————————	
CS 380P: Parallel Systems	
CS 380P: Parallel SystemsFall 2020	
<ul> <li>Teaching Assistant for Graduate Course</li> <li>Graded assignments and assisted students to develop intuition for parallel programming paradigms across several languages and standard libraries</li> </ul>	
<b>CS 373: Software Engineering</b>	
<ul> <li>Lectured on web technologies and best practices, assisted students with course content, and graded assignments</li> </ul>	
<b>CS 309: Computational Intelligence in Game Research FRI</b>	
<ul> <li>Instructed students on the principles of machine learning, optimization, and neuroevolution in fun simulated game environments</li> </ul>	
<ul> <li>Directed incoming undergraduates on how to develop, record, and present their ideas and findings for reproducible research</li> </ul>	
ACTIVITIES ————————————————————————————————————	
Machine Learning Data Prefetching Competition	

<b>Association of Computing Machinery</b> Fall The University of Texas at Austin Chapter Member	2015 - Present
<ul> <li>Participated in local competitions to improve skills in problem solving und algorithmic constraints</li> </ul>	er specific
<ul> <li>Machine Learning and Data Science Student Organization Spring 2010</li> <li>Attended walk-throughs and Kaggle-esque competitions to develop and gwith applying machine learning techniques effectively and to more real-weighted.</li> </ul>	gain experience
Information and Systems Security SocietyFall 2015  Competed in Capture-The-Flag events and attended workshops on various	
AWARDS ————————————————————————————————————	
TIDES Advance Summer Research Fellowship  · Awarded to undergraduate students working on advanced research with a supervisor	
Freshman Research Initiative Fellowship  Awarded to freshmen to continue with their research proposal from the FF their research educator / principal investigator	
Distinguished College Scholar / Students of High Academic Achievement	2017 - 2019
Kemp-Forman Memorial Endowed Presidential Scholarship	2017 - 2018
Tracor/Frank McBee, Jr. Scholarship	2016 - 2017
SKILLS —————	

- **Languages**: Python, C/C++, Go, Rust, Java, Julia, MATLAB, Lua, HTML/CSS, JavaScript/JSX, x86 ASM, SQL, LaTeX
- **Libraries**: numpy, PyTorch, TensorFlow, sklearn, scipy, matplotlib/seaborn, React, Flask, OpenGL
- Other Skills: Unix Systems (Ubuntu, Debian, Arch Linux), Vietnamese